

■ tylerjpoore@gmail.com■ 307-609-1035• New York, NY

in tylerjpoore-1825 ♠ Pooret

# **EDUCATION**

Columbia 2010 to University 2013
MS Organic Chemistry 2013

Rensselaer
Polytechnic 2010
Institute
BS/MS Chemistry 2010

# **SUMMARY**

I am an entrepreneur-turned data scientist, ML/AI enthusiast. Currently, I am a Springboard Data Science Fellow with project experience in data analysis and visualization, NLP, machine learning, and deep learning. I have over 7 years of experience in market research, adoption strategy, and product development for early-stage biotech companies. Outside of work I am an avid skier, fitness nerd, and love 80's synth-pop.

## **SKILLS**

**DATA SCIENCE:** Python, SQL, Data Analysis, Data Visualization, Machine Learning, NLP, Bayesian Statistics, MySQL, Hadoop, Deep Learning, Tensorflow, Inferential Statistics

ENTREPRENEURSHIP: User Engagement, Prototyping, Public Speaking, Shareholder Engagement, Lean Startup,

Startup Operations, Medical Devices, Market Research & Strategy, Fundraising

**PRODUCT DEVELOPMENT (CHEMISTRY):** Organic Chemistry, Polymer Chemistry, Natural Products, Product Characterization, Nanotechnology, Product Manager, Product Roadmap

# **EMPLOYMENT**

SPRINGBOARD New York
Data Science Fellow Jan. 2021 to Current, Jan. 2021 to Current

550+ hours of hands-on curriculum, with 1:1 industry expert mentor oversight, and completion of 2 in-depth capstone projects. Mastering skills in Python, SQL, data analysis, data visualization, hypothesis testing, and machine learning. Machine Learning experience for time-series analysis, deep learning, model deployment, NLP, image processing, and Hadoop.

Capstone Project 1: Predicting Stock Movement using Executive's Tweets

IROS, LLC.

New York, NY
Co-Founder

Mar. 2015 to Nov. 2019

Co-Founded biotech company that 3D printed biomimetic hydrogel drug-releasing scaffolds as anti-biofilm dissolvable sleeves for implantable medical devices.

EXSPONGE, INC.

New York, NY

Nov. 2013 to Jan. 2015

Development of novel, covalently-bound antimicrobial fibers that are safe, non-leaching, and don't lead to antimicrobial resistance.

### **PROJECTS**

#### **CONCUSSION PREDICTION WITH TRANSFER LEARNING**

Using an RNN to predict concussions with a pre-trained model

#### STOCK MOVEMENT PREDICTION USING TWITTER

Mar. 2021 to Sept. 2021

Sept. 2021 to Current

5 years of stock and twitter data were collected for 6 companies and their executives. Stock movement was predicted using SVM and Logistic Regression Classifiers with features engineered from the company executive's tweets.

# **ACTIVITIES**

### PETFINDER.MY - PAWPULARITY CONTEST · kaggle competition group